Guide to the Harold Dwight Lasswell Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- General Files, 1920-1978; Series I; 44 linear feet (106 boxes, 2 folio boxes)
  - Padover, Saul K., 1941-1959, 1965-1974 (Box 76, Folder 958-959)
  - Parker, Benjamin M., 1940-1942, 1951-1957 (Box 76, Folder 960)
  - Patna University
    See: box 97, folder 1179
  - Peace Corps, 1964-1966 (Box 76, Folder 961)
  - Peace Research Institute, 1961-1974 (Box 76, Folder 962)
  - Penna, Frank, 1969-1978 (Box 76, Folder 963-964)
  - Perles, Julia, 1958-1966 (Box 76, Folder 965)
  - Perry, Charner, 1943, 1956-1971 (Box 77, Folder 966)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1943-1970 (Box 77, Folder 967)
  - Pi Sigma Alpha, 1960-1974 (Box 77, Folder 968)
  - Pilpel, Harriet F., 1957-1963 (Box 77, Folder 969)
  - Polak, Fred L., 1955-1957 (Box 77, Folder 970)
  - Policy Sciences Council, 1944 (Box 77, Folder 971)
  - Policy Sciences Foundation, Inc., Policy Sciences Center, Inc., 1944-1976, undated (Box 77, Folder 972-974)
    See also: box 13, folders 149-154 See also: box 53, folders 749-753 See also: box 62, folders 834-835 See also: box 62, folders 838-840 See also: box 76, folders 963-964 See also: box 90, folder 1106
  - Policy Studies Organization
    See: box 67, folder 885-886
  - Pool, Ithiel de Sola, 1947-1974 (Box 77, Folder 975-976)
  - Pregel, Boris
  - Princeton University Press, 1942-1973 (Box 77, Folder 977)
  - Probert, Walter, 1957-1974 (Box 78, Folder 978)
  - Psychiatry
    See: box 99, folder 1209
  - Public Affairs Institute, 1951-1964 (Box 78, Folder 979)
  - Public Opinion Quarterly, 1943-1975 (Box 78, Folder 980)
    See also: box 30, folder 387
  - Q, 1948-1973 (Box 78, Folder 981)
  - R, 1938-1967 (Box 78, Folder 982-992)
  - R, 1968-1978, undated (Box 79, Folder 993-997)
  - Radio Liberty
    See: box 86, folder 1066
  - Rand Corporation, 1947-1948 (Box 79, Folder 998-1000)
  - Rand Corporation, 1949-1977 (Box 80, Folder 1001-1006)
    See also: box 38, folders 516-526 See also: box 89, folders 1094-1098 See also: box 19, folders 241-245 See also: box 42, folders 581-584 See also: box 46, folder 638 See also: box 48, folder 680 See also: box 52, folders 730-731 See also: box 57, folders 790-792 See also: box 90, folder 1106
  - Ray, Donald
    See: box 3, folders 35-36 See: box 69, folder 902
  - Redlich, Frederick C., 1948, 1952-1973 (Box 80, Folder 1007)
  - Reid (Helen Dwight) Educational Foundation, Inc.
    See: box 42, folders 591-592
  - Reisman, David, 1946-1978 (Box 80, Folder 1008)
  - Reisman, W. Michael, 1970-1977 (Box 81, Folder 1009-1011)
  - Research for Better Schools, Inc., 1973-1977 (Box 81, Folder 1012)
  - Rice, Stuart A., 1966-1969 (Box 81, Folder 1013)
  - Riznik, Joseph Quentin, 1951-1977, undated (Box 81, Folder 1014)
  - Roazen, Paul, 1965-1973 (Box 81, Folder 1015)
  - Robinson, James A., 1959-1975 (Box 81, Folder 1016-1017)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1939-1978 (Box 81, Folder 1018)
    See also: box 64, folder 852
  - Rogers, Walter S., 1946-1951 (Box 81, Folder 1019)
  - Rogow, Arnold A., 1948, 1955-1964 (Box 81, Folder 1020)
  - Rogow, Arnold A., 1966-1975, undated (Box 82, Folder 1021)
  - Rolle, Andrew, 1969-1976 (Box 82, Folder 1022)
  - Rosenthal, Douglas, 1966-1970 (Box 82, Folder 1023-1025)
  - Rosenthal, Howard, 1961-1967 (Box 82, Folder 1026)
  - Rosten, Leo, 1942-1973 (Box 82, Folder 1027-1029)
  - Routledge & Kegan Paul Ltd., 1943-1976 (Box 82, Folder 1030)
  - Routt, Garland C., 1940s-1952 (Box 83, Folder 1031-1032)
  - Rowe, David N., 1940-1967 (Box 83, Folder 1033-1034)
  - Rubenstein, Robert, 1959-1975, undated (Box 83, Folder 1035)
  - Rucker, W. Ray, 1959-1973 (Box 83, Folder 1036)
  - Ruml, Beardsley, 1945-1956 (Box 83, Folder 1037)
  - Russett, Bruce M., 1962-1971 (Box 83, Folder 1038)
  - S, 1936-1965 (Box 84, Folder 1039-1049)
  - S, 1966-1971 (Box 85, Folder 1050-1058)
  - S, 1972-1978, undated (Box 86, Folder 1059-1062)
  - Sage Publications, Inc., 1967-1974 (Box 86, Folder 1063)
  - Salk Institute, 1968 (Box 86, Folder 1064)
  - Salmon Committee on Psychiatry and Mental Hygiene, 1947-1975 (Box 86, Folder 1065)
  - Sapir, Edward
  - Sargeant, Howland H., 1947-1948, 1960, 1967-1970 (Box 86, Folder 1066)
    See also: box 16, folders 195-205 See also: box 93, folder 1147
  - Saturday Review, 1948-1963, 1969 (Box 86, Folder 1067)
  - Saxon, James, 1969 (Box 86, Folder 1068)
  - Schachter, Oscar, 1965-1973, undated (Box 87, Folder 1069)
  - Schelling, Thomas C.
    See: box 40, folders 549-553
  - Schimel, John L., 1960-1961 (Box 87, Folder 1070)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur M.
  - Schubert, Glendon, 1962-1969 (Box 87, Folder 1071)
  - Schuster, George N.
  - Schwebel, Stephen M., 1952-1978 (Box 87, Folder 1072)
    See also: box 7, folders 87-91 See also: box 28, folders 366-367
  - Science and Behavior Press
    See: box 48, folder 677
  - Serdakovsky, Lev, 1950-1951 (Box 87, Folder 1073)
  - Sereno, Renzo, 1946-1966 (Box 87, Folder 1074)
  - Shapley, Harlow, 1942-1968, undated (Box 87, Folder 1075)
  - Shih, Henry
  - Shihs, Edward, 1940-1972, undated (Box 87, Folder 1076-1078)
  - Sills, David L.
    See: box 47, folder 657
  - Silverman, Sam, 1969-1973 (Box 87, Folder 1079)
  - Simulmatics Corporation
  - Sinha, S.K., 1967-1969 (Box 87, Folder 1080)
  - Skolnick, Jerome, 1957-1966, undated (Box 87, Folder 1081-1082)
  - Smith, Bruce Lannes, 1940-1974, undated (Box 88, Folder 1083-1086)
  - Smith, Datus
    See: box 35, folders 470-476 See: box 77, folder 977
  - Snyder, Richard C., 1956-1969 (Box 88, Folder 1087)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1942-1974 (Box 88, Folder 1088)
  - Somit, Albert, 1964-1975 (Box 88, Folder 1089)
  - Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group of the Asia Society, 1970-1973, undated (Box 88, Folder 1090-1093)
    See also: box 19, folders 237-240 See also: box 19, folders 241-245 See also: box 66, folder 867
  - Soviet System and Western Democracy
    See: box 52, folder 735
  - Speier, Hans, 1941-1973 (Box 89, Folder 1094-1098)
  - Stanford University, 1955-1970 (Box 89, Folder 1099)
  - State University of New York at Albany, 1965-1972 (Box 89, Folder 1100-1101)
    See also: box 66, folder 871
  - State University of New York at Buffalo, 1963-1972 (Box 89, Folder 1102)
  - Stephens, Richard H., 1963-1973 (Box 89, Folder 1103)
  - Stern, H. Peter, 1957-1976 (Box 90, Folder 1104-1105)
  - Stewart (George W.) Publisher, Inc., 1949-1976, undated (Box 90, Folder 1106)
  - Stewart, Milton, 1946-1969 (Box 90, Folder 1107)
  - Stoessinger, John G.
    See: box 26, folder 327
  - Stokowski, Leopold, 1942-1945 (Box 90, Folder 1108)
  - Stone, Philip J., 1965-1971 (Box 90, Folder 1109)
  - Student Forum on International Order and World Peace, 1967-1970 (Box 90, Folder 1110)
  - Sullivan, Harry Stack
  - Swift, Otis P., 1946-1954 (Box 90, Folder 1111)
  - T, 1939-1966 (Box 90, Folder 1112-1116)
  - T, 1967-1977, undated (Box 91, Folder 1117-1119)
  - Taylor, George E., 1947-1969 (Box 91, Folder 1120)
  - Taylor, Telford, 1956-1961 (Box 91, Folder 1121)
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association of America, 1938-1976 (Box 91, Folder 1122)
  - Temple University, 1972-1976 (Box 91, Folder 1123-1125)
    See also: box 59, folder 804
  - Thompson, William P., 1966-1977 (Box 91, Folder 1126)
  - Tomasic, Dinko, 1946-1973 (Box 92, Folder 1127)
  - Trends Research, Inc.
  - Triffin, Robert, 1967-1974 (Box 92, Folder 1128)
  - Triska, Jan, 1953-1965 (Box 92, Folder 1129)
  - Truman, David B., 1941-1960 (Box 92, Folder 1130)
  - Tyler, Ralph W., 1952-1973 (Box 92, Folder 1131)
  - U, 1940-1976, undated (Box 92, Folder 1132-1137)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization, 1950-1973 (Box 92, Folder 1138)
  - United Nations Institute for Training and Research, 1966-1973 (Box 93, Folder 1139)
    See also: box 87, folder 1069
  - United States (government), 1941-1972, undated (Box 93, Folder 1140-1141)
  - United States. Dept. of Agriculture, 1946 (Box 93, Folder 1142)
    See also: box 83, folders 1031-1032
  - United States. Dept. of Defense, 1949-1970 (Box 93, Folder 1143-1145)
  - United States. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare, 1957-1970 (Box 93, Folder 1146)
  - United States. Dept. of State, 1943, 1945 (Box 93, Folder 1147)
  - United States. Dept. of State, 1946-1971 (Box 94, Folder 1148-1153)
    See also: box 16, folders 195-205 See also: box 62, folder 841
  - United States. Dept. of State. Office of International Information and Cultural Affairs. Program Planning Board, 1946 (Box 94, Folder 1154-1156)
  - United States. Dept. of State. Office of Public Affairs. Division of Public Liason. Public Attitudes Branch, 1945-1946 (Box 95, Folder 1157)
  - United States. Executive Office of the President. Coordinator of Information, 1941-1942 (Box 95, Folder 1158)
  - United States. Executive Office of the President. Office for Emergency Management. Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs. Bureau of Latin American Research, 1942-1944 (Box 95, Folder 1159)
  - United States. Executive Office of the President. Office for Emergency Management. Office of Facts and Figures, 1942 (Box 95, Folder 1160)
    See also: box 51, folders 725-726
  - United States. Executive Office of the President, Office of War Information, 1942-1943, 1945 (Box 95, Folder 1161-1162)
  - United States. General Services Administration, National Archives and Records Service. Archives Advisory Council, 1968-1971 (Box 95, Folder 1163)
    See also: box 66, folder 869
  - United States. Office of Censorship, 1942-1943 (Box 96, Folder 1164)
  - United States. War Department, 1942-1949 (Box 96, Folder 1165)
  - United States Information Agency, 1955-1973 (Box 96, Folder 1166)
  - University Centers for Rationale Alternatives
    See: box 28, folder 361
  - University of California, Los Angeles, 1965-1970 (Box 96, Folder 1167)
  - University of Chicago, 1921-1974 (Box 96, Folder 1168)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1942-1974 (Box 96, Folder 1169)
  - University of Illinois, 1960-1974 (Box 96, Folder 1170)
  - University of Illinois Press, 1954-1971 (Box 96, Folder 1170)
  - University of Michigan, 1946-1973 (Box 96, Folder 1171)
  - University of Michigan Press, 1967-1968 (Box 96, Folder 1171)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1948-1974 (Box 96, Folder 1172)
  - University of Virginia. School of Law
    See: box 30, folder 397
  - V, 1936-1959 (Box 96, Folder 1173-1174)
  - V, 1960-1976 (Box 97, Folder 1175-1177)
  - Van Meter, Galen, 1945-1954 (Box 97, Folder 1178)
  - Varma, Vishwanath Prasad, 1965-1972 (Box 97, Folder 1179)
  - W, 1938-1966 (Box 97, Folder 1180-1188)
  - W, 1967-1977, undated (Box 98, Folder 1189-1196)
  - Wallach, Sidney, 1946-1966, undated (Box 98, Folder 1197)
    See: box 5, folders 53-57 See: box 16, folders 195-205 See: box 26, folders 325-326 See: box 43, folder 608
  - Waller, Theodore, 1941-1976 (Box 98, Folder 1198-1199)
    See also: box 3, folder 39
  - Waples, Douglas, 1941-1947 (Box 98, Folder 1200)
  - Washington School of Psychiatry
  - Watts (Franklin) Inc., 1961-1963 (Box 98, Folder 1201)
  - Wayne State University, 1954-1969 (Box 98, Folder 1202)
  - Westin, Alan F., 1957-1969 (Box 99, Folder 1203)
  - Weston, Burns, 1969-1975 (Box 99, Folder 1204-1205)
  - Weyrauch, Walter O., 1958-1974 (Box 99, Folder 1206-1207)
  - White, John F.
    See:box 32, folders 422-425
  - White, Leonard D., 1943-1956 (Box 99, Folder 1208)
  - White (William Alanson) Psychiatric Foundation, 1936-1963 (Box 99, Folder 1209)
    See also: box 53, folders 749-753
  - Whitelaw, Aubrey H., 1954-1969 (Box 99, Folder 1210)
  - Whitney (John Hay) Foundation, 1950-1953 (Box 99, Folder 1211)
  - Widner, Ralph R.
    See: box 2, folders 15-16
  - Wissenschaftszentrum Berlin, 1970-1971 (Box 99, Folder 1212)
  - Wittfogel, Karl A., 1946-1948 (Box 99, Folder 1213)
  - Wolf, Charles, Jr.
    See: box 79, folders 998-1000
  - Wood, Bryce
    See: box 88, folder 1088
  - World Academy of Art and Science: general, 1962-1968 March (Box 99, Folder 1214)
  - World Academy of Art and Science: general, 1968 April-1975 (Box 100, Folder 1215-1227)
  - World Academy of Art and Science
    - General, 1976 (Box 101, Folder 1228-1231)
    - Brochures and Newsletters, 1966-1969 (Box 101, Folder 1232)
    - Financial records, 1973-1976 (Box 101, Folder 1233)
    - Joint Conference with American Geographical Society, 1967, 1969-1970 (Box 101, Folder 1234-1235)
    - World University, 1968-1970 (Box 101, Folder 1236-1238)
  - World Academy of Art and Science: general, undated (Box 102, Folder 1239)
  - World Federal Authority Committee, 1972-1976 (Box 102, Folder 1240)
  - World Future Society, 1967-1976 (Box 102, Folder 1241)
  - World Habeas Corpus
    See: box 53, folders 749-753 See: box 62, folders 834-835
  - World Law Fund
    - General, 1965-1973 (Box 102, Folder 1242-1243)
    - Research on Selected Aspects of Childrens' International Beliefs, 1969 (Box 102, Folder 1244)
    - World Order Models Project, 1966 - 1968 May (Box 102, Folder 1245-1249)
    - World Order Models Project, 1968 June - 1976, undated (Box 103, Folder 1250-1257)
      See also: box 33, folders 450-451
  - Wright, Arthur and Mary, 1948-1973 (Box 103, Folder 1258)
  - Wright, Quincy, 1947-1967 (Box 103, Folder 1259)
  - X, 1963, 1970 (Box 103, Folder 1260)
  - Y, 1941-1951 (Box 103, Folder 1261)
  - Y, 1952-1976, undated (Box 104, Folder 1262-1263)
  - Yakobson, Sergius, 1942-1970 (Box 104, Folder 1264)
    See also: box 185, folder 199
  - Yale University
    General note
    See also: box 65, folders 861-862 box 68, folders 889-892 box 83, folder 1038
    - General, 1943-1973, undated (Box 104, Folder 1265-1266)
    - Administration, 1941-1970 (Box 104, Folder 1267)
    - Committee on National Policy, 1946-1959 (Box 104, Folder 1268)
    - Department of Political Science
      - General, 1952-1969 (Box 104, Folder 1269)
      - Office for Advanced Political Studies
        - General, 1967-1969 (Box 104, Folder 1270-1273)
        - Development Decision Seminar, 1969-1971 (Box 105, Folder 1274)
        - Seminar (collegium) on the future, 1967-1969 (Box 105, Folder 1275-1277)
      - Political Science Research Library, 1960-1971 (Box 105, Folder 1278)
    - Law School
      See also: Folio boxes 106A and 106B
      - General, 1935-1971, undated (Box 105, Folder 1279-1281)
      - General, 1935-1975, undated (Box 106, Folder 1282)
      - Chart room project, 1959-1960 (Box 106, Folder 1283)
    - Political Data Program, 1964-1967 (Box 106, Folder 1284-1285)
    - World Political Data and Analysis Program, 1967-1970 (Box 106, Folder 1284-1285)
      See also: box 65, folders 861-862 See also: box 68, folders 889-892 See also: box 83, folder 1038
    - Seminar on the Future of World Politics, 1968 (Box 106, Folder 1286)
  - Yale University Press, 1945-1977 (Box 106, Folder 1287-1288)
  - Yarmolinsky, Adam, 1959-1967 (Box 106, Folder 1289)
  - Yu, Frederick T.C., 1953-1962 (Box 106, Folder 1290)
  - Z, 1938-1976 (Box 106, Folder 1291)
  - Zawodny, Jay, 1963-1965 (Box 106, Folder 1292)
  - Zitta, Victor, 1956-1976 (Box 106, Folder 1293)
  - Zwick, Charles
    See: box 16, folders 195-205
  - Unidentified (Box 106, Folder 1294)
  - Folio boxes
    - Yale University. Law School. Chart room project - charts (Box 106A–106B)
- Writings, 1923-1981; Series II; 25 linear feet (57 boxes)
  The Writings series includes materials received in the original gift of Lasswell papers to the Manuscripts and Archives Department as well as copies of writings received in later additions to the papers. In 1991 the series was reorganized to accommodate these additional writings. This reorganization relied heavily on Harold D. Lasswell: an annotated bibliography (New Haven Press: New Haven, Conn., 1990) by Rodney Muth. The bibliography was used to identify previously unidentified or misidentified items. Not all items listed in this bibliography, however, are included in the papers.
  The series begins with a box of notecards representing an early bibliography of Lasswell's writings. The series is then arranged in sections as follows:
  Published for materials relating to Lasswell's published books and articles. Also included are the radio scripts for "Human Nature in Action." Since in the Muth bibliography, as a general rule, Lasswell's speeches and lectures are treated as unpublished, these items are not included in this section. For any title the files may contain outlines, notes, manuscript drafts, revised drafts, printed copies, and research material, as well as contracts, communications with publishers, and lists of persons to whom copies of the work were sent.
  Unpublished for those works identified in the Muth bibliography in the section "Unpublished Works," as well as other items not classified by Muth. The section includes speeches, memoranda, and materials intended for publication but which were never published. The sub-section alphabetical contains only those works without dates and is arranged alphabetically by title. The sub-section chronological includes those works listed in Muth with dates as well as additional dated items not included in Muth. Undated items not listed in the Muth bibliography are arranged at the end of the sub-section.
  The series includes a number of outlines and sketches which appear to have been created in the process of Lasswell's writing for publication but cannot be identified with any title or work. These along with fragments of manuscripts are arranged in the section Unidentified.
  The series also includes a section Forthcoming, which contains drafts for the book Law, Science, and Policy. The volume, when published, will represent the culmination of the long scholarly collaboration between Lasswell and Myres MacDougal. The section includes material from a course of the same name, taught by them, as well as outlines and draft revisions that document the volume's development and revision.
  At the end of the series in the section Card Files, Extracts, and Notes there is material, apparently collected or created in Lasswell's research, but which cannot be identified with a specific work.
  - Published
    - Bibliography-note cards, 1923-1947 (Box 107)
    - 1923, 1926-1927, 1930-1931, 1933-1939 (Box 108, Folder 1-11)
    - 1939 (Box 109, Folder 12)
    - 1940: radio scripts for "Human Nature in Action" (Box 109A, Folder 16-17, Box 109, Folder 13-15)
    - 1941-1945 (Box 110, Folder 18-23)
    - 1946 (Box 111, Folder 24)
    - 1946: World Politics Faces Economics (Box 111, Folder 25)
    - 1947-1949 (Box 111, Folder 26-28)
    - 1949: Mass Communications (Box 111, Folder 29)
    - 1949: Language of Politics (Box 112, Folder 30)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 112, Folder 31-32)
    - 1951: World Revolution of Our Time (Radir project) (Box 113, Folder 33-34)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 113, Folder 35-37)
    - 1954-1957 (Box 114, Folder 38-42)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 115, Folder 42a-45)
    - 1960-1965 (Box 116, Folder 46-52)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 117, Folder 53-55)
    - 1966: The Sharing of Power in a Psychiatric Hospital (Box 117, Folder 56-57)
    - 1966: The Sharing of Power in a Psychiatric Hospital (Box 118, Folder 58-63)
    - 1966: The Sharing of Power in a Psychiatric Hospital (Box 119, Folder 64)
    - 1967 (Box 119, Folder 65-66)
    - 1967: Formosa, China, and the United Nations (Box 119, Folder 67)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 120, Folder 68-70)
    - 1969 (Box 121, Folder 71-72)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 122, Folder 73-75)
    - 1971 (Box 123, Folder 76-77)
    - 1971: Peasants, Power and Applied Social Change (Box 123, Folder 78-79)
    - 1971: Policy Orientation of Political Science (Box 123, Folder 80-81)
    - 1971: Propaganda Technique in World War I (reprint) (Box 123, Folder 82)
    - 1972-1975 (Box 124, Folder 83-88)
    - 1975-1978 (Box 125, Folder 89-95)
    - 1979: Signature of Power, preliminary matter (Box 125, Folder 96)
    - 1979: Signature of Power, preliminary matter (Box 126, Folder 97)
    - 1979: Signature of Power, notecards (Box 126, Folder 98)
    - 1979: Signature of Power (Box 126, Folder 99-100)
    - 1979: Signature of Power, draft A (Box 126, Folder 101-102)
    - 1979: Signature of Power, draft A (Box 127, Folder 103)
    - 1979: Signature of Power, draft B (Box 127, Folder 104)
    - 1979: Signature of Power, draft C, Part I (Box 127, Folder 105-106)
    - 1979: Signature of Power, draft C, Part II (Box 127, Folder 107-108)
    - 1979: Signature of Power, draft D, Part I (Box 127, Folder 109)
    - 1979: Signature of Power, draft D, Part II (Box 127, Folder 110)
    - 1979: Signature of Power, draft E (Box 128, Folder 111)
    - 1979: Signature of Power, draft F (Box 128, Folder 112)
    - 1980 (Box 128, Folder 113-114a)
    - 1981 (Box 128, Folder 115)
    - 1992: Law, Science and Policy
      See: boxes 144-147
  - Unpublished: alphabetical
    - A (Box 129, Folder 116)
    - Ch-Con (Box 129, Folder 117)
    - "The Configurative Method" (Box 129, Folder 118)
    - Confirm-Cou (Box 129, Folder 119)
    - D (Box 129, Folder 120)
    - E (Box 129, Folder 121)
    - F (Box 129, Folder 122)
    - G (Box 129, Folder 123)
    - I (Box 129, Folder 124)
    - Ma-Me (Box 129, Folder 125)
    - Mo-My (Box 129, Folder 126)
    - N (Box 129, Folder 127)
    - Po (Box 129, Folder 128)
    - "The Political Science of Contemporary China" (Box 129, Folder 129)
    - Politics (Box 129, Folder 130)
    - "Power in Political Theory" (Box 129, Folder 131)
    - "The Pre-Adult in Social Process" (Box 129, Folder 132)
    - Prel-Pu (Box 129, Folder 133)
    - Rec (Box 130, Folder 134)
    - "Resettlement Communities: A Study of the Problems of Personalizing Administration" (Box 130, Folder 135-139)
    - Resp-Ro (Box 130, Folder 140)
    - "Sex and Politics" (Box 130, Folder 141-143)
    - "Sex and Politics" (Box 131, Folder 144-146)
    - So (Box 131, Folder 147)
    - St (Box 131, Folder 148)
    - "Symbol, Power and Crisis" (Box 131, Folder 149-152)
    - Te (Box 132, Folder 153)
    - To (Box 132, Folder 154)
    - V (Box 132, Folder 155)
    - W (Box 132, Folder 156)
    - Untitled (Box 132, Folder 157)
  - Unpublished: chronological
    - 1934, 1941, 1944 (Box 133, Folder 158-166)
    - 1944: "The Creation of an Institute of Legal and Social Science" (Box 133, Folder 167)
    - 1945 (Box 133, Folder 168)
    - 1945: "The Use of Scientists in Atomic Bomb Control" (Box 133, Folder 169)
    - [ca. 1939-1945] (Box 133, Folder 170-171)
    - 1946, 1948-1949 (Box 133, Folder 172-174)
    - 1951-1952, 1954-1962, 1964-1968 (Box 134, Folder 175-192)
    - 1968: "Value Dictionary," Vol. I (Box 135, Folder 193)
    - 1968: "Value Dictionary," Vol. II (Box 136, Folder 194)
    - 1968: "Value Dictionary," Vol. III (Box 136, Folder 195)
    - 1968: "Value Dictionary" (Box 137, Folder 196-197)
    - 1968: "Value Dictionary," computer cards (Box 138)
    - 1968: "Value Dictionary," computer cards (Box 139)
    - 1968: "Value Dictionary," computer cards (Box 140)
    - 1968: "Value Dictionary," computer cards (Box 141)
    - 1968: "Value Dictionary," computer cards (Box 142)
    - 1969: "Appraising the Effectiveness of A Foundation's Activities" (Box 143, Folder 198)
    - 1972, 1974-1977, undated (Box 143, Folder 199-209)
  - Unidentified
    - Fragments (Box 143, Folder 210)
    - Outlines, sketches (Box 143, Folder 211-216)
  - Forthcoming [published 1992]
    - Law, Science and Policy (Box 144, Folder 217-220)
    - Law, Science and Policy (Box 145, Folder 221-224)
    - Law, Science and Policy (Box 146)
    - Law, Science and Policy (Box 147)
  - Card files, extracts, notes
    - Card files
      - Sciences (Box 148)
      - Charts (Box 149)
      - Social Process (Box 150)
      - Symbols cards, English magazines (Box 151)
      - Communication (Box 152)
      - A - Z concepts (Box 153)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 154–161)
    - Extracts (Box 162, Folder 225-237)
    - Extracts (Box 163, Folder 238-244)